<Document>
  # Right to Appeal

    Anyone under the jurisdiction of the UCMJ has the right to appeal their punishment to their choice of either the Adjutant, CMP, Commander or High Command via fax. If either selected authority was involved in the arrest, they must recuse themselves and designate an uninvolved officer. They may only handle the appeal if no alternative is available. Whoever is handling the appeal has the final say in the outcome of the appeal.

  ## Appeal Outcomes & Handling

    A charge cannot be removed by appeal if the prisoner is found guilty; however, the person who handles the appeal can process the appeal as:

      - A valid charge, no modification.
      - Modify the charge to a lower charge.
      - Reduce the punishment for the charge to the minimum punishment.
      - Remove a charge for which the prisoner is found innocent.

  Appeals must be handled before demotions and NJPs. Appealing prisoners should have their brig timers set and running while the appeal is being processed. Personnel may be placed in holding awaiting their appeal if it had no brig sentence.

  Appeals must be held in an enclosed room with:

    - The prisoner
    - The appeal handler
    - The arresting officer
    - The sentencing officer
    - The CMP if available
    - Any relevant evidence or items

  A recording of the appeal must be made.

  You may only appeal a sentence once. If your appeal is denied, modified, reduced or removed, you may not seek another appeal.

  ## Military Appeals
    - May appeal to the CMP, Adjutant, or Commander.
    - Members of command staff may only appeal to someone of higher rank than themselves. If none is available, they may submit a written appeal to High Command or the Provost.
    - Permanently brigged military personnel who have had their appeal denied or waived their right may submit a written request to High Command or the Provost as a final attempt.

  ## Civilian Appeals
    - May appeal to any member of command staff.
    - Appeals must be submitted in written format, including any relevant information such as:
    - Items on their person
    - Military Police statements
    - Permanently brigged civilians who have had their appeal denied or waived their right may submit a written request to High Command or the Provost as a final attempt.

  ## Appeal Limits
    - Appeals may only happen once. Waiving your right to appeal removes any future opportunity to appeal.
    - Appeals to High Command are reserved for members of Command Staff unless otherwise stated.

  ## Appeal Timing
  Appeals must be conducted within 15 minutes.
  If this timeframe is exceeded:
    - The individual requesting the appeal is to be released from all charges.
    - The sentencing officer or assigned appeal handler may be charged with Neglect of Duty if the delay is found to be intentional and without valid reason.

  ## Appeal Delays
  Appeals may only be postponed if:
    - There are active threats on the ship or installation requiring immediate response.
    - Riots or jailbreaks are occurring.
    - The prisoner requires medical treatment.
    - Another appeal is currently being processed.
    - The prisoner has escaped or cannot be physically present.
</Document>