<Document>
  # Arresting Procedures

  Should an Officer order an arrest for a crime, MPs/Law Enforcement must carry out the arrest; however, the alleged offence must still be properly investigated. If the arrest is determined to be false or a severe misuse of authority, the Officer who ordered it is to be charged with Prevarication.

  ## Arresting a Suspect
    - Take down the Suspect if they resist and securely restrain them.
    - Non-lethal force must be used unless the suspect is armed with a lethal weapon and has shown intent to use it.
    - Move the Suspect to a holding cell.

  ## Command Arrests
    When arresting a member of command (CO, XO, JOs, etc.), a facsimile must be sent to the Marshal Office as soon as the individual is charged, including a detailed report outlining the reasoning. The CMP must be present for the arrest if available. The command member must be read their appeal rights in full and, if they are the acting commander of the operation, are to be given 10 minutes to properly hand over command. This may be extended in emergency situations (EX. shipside emergencies).

  ## Detainment Authority
    The follow regulations apply in the regards of Command ordering detainment or being detained.
      - All orders from the detained command personnel are null and void, and shall not be followed by anyone.
      - Command may not order the arrest of someone on grounds of suspicion
      - Command may not pardon anyone of a crime, unless for the sakes of an emergency, this does not apply to Capital crimes, or violent crimes (i.e. Murder)
      - The CMO may order arrests on the grounds of Insanity if done so after a proper examination with documentation. Under no other circumstances shall a person be ordered to be arrested for Insanity.

  ## Do Not Revive Orders
    The follow regulations apply for DNR orders issued by MPs or Command
      - DNRs may not be issued by the XO or CO without proper documentation received from HighComm.
      - CO or XO may request for a DNR through HighComm.
      - If a person requests a DNR from the CMO for themselves and it is approved, it must be followed by law, chargeable by VoL (major crimes).

  ## Field Arrests
    These refer to arrests performed in the area of operations.
      - Anyone may detain personnel of their faction that commit a major or capital crime, but must detain personnel of their faction by orders of the MP/Law Enforcement, commander, or any officer.
      - Anyone may detain personnel deploying unauthorized, even without orders to do so.
      - Personnel detained should be passed onto the MP/Law Enforcement or an Officer in a secure area when possible.
      - MPs/Law Enforcement MAY leave the FOB to detain or arrest members of their faction who have committed any offense, but must disengage and return to the FOB if attacked by anyone other than the suspect they are pursuing.
</Document>
