<Document>
  # Command Regulations

  ## Command Staff
    Command staff consist of the following ranks and military roles.
      - The Commander.
      - The Adjutant.
      - Junior Officers and all of their rankings (CMO, LO, IO, EO, CMP.)
      - Advisors
      - Anyone with the rank of O6 or higher.

  ## Command Arms
    Command must abide by the following regulations regarding arming themselves on the ship or in the field:
      - Command may not take any type of special weapon or heavy weaponry from Req or Vendors, and may only use standard issue arms found in their respective armoury, or rifleman prep. (This does not include magazines)
      - Command Staff are allowed to operate special weapons only if no one else in the vicinity is doing so, or there is an emergency going on.

  ## Conduct of Briefing
    The Commander must ensure that personnel receive a thorough briefing before deployment and operations. If a Commander is not present to ensure a proper briefing is held, the chain of command is to follow.
      - It must be performed in an area where a proper inspection of personnel can be held and where personnel can hear any orders.
      - Areas that interfere with non-combat personnel must be avoided, for example, the medbay.
      - Briefings at a minimum must include all deploying faction command (SLs, JOs, etc).

  ## Command Field Deployment
    Deployments must be for the sake of the personnel and operation, and not for the personal glory of the Command Staff. At least one member of the Command Staff must remain on the ship/installation to man the CIC at all times.

  When Deployed:
    - The deploying Command Staff must still command and communicate frequently with their faction.
    - Combat should be reserved when assisting personnel in a supporting capacity, in defence of others and self, or directly leading an offensive manoeuvre.
    - They should avoid unnecessarily putting themselves in danger and remain close to personnel to focus on providing clear orders.
    - IO's are exempt from the above as their job often entails covert operations for intelligence gathering and distruption of enemy backlines and logistics.
</Document>
