<Document>
  # Dropships and Aircraft

    These regulations govern the authority, modification and operational use of all aircraft and dropships.

  ## Flight Crew Authority
    - Flight Crew may modify their aircraft with permission from a member of the command, as long as the modifications provide a benefit in mind, not solely for decorative purposes. 
    - Commander or Adjutant may deny any modifications made to the aircraft.
    - Flight crew may deny access to personnel onboard their ship unless said personnel are deploying to the area of operations or returning from them.
    - Flight Crew may remove any personnel, except Command Staff, for any reason unless doing so would breach the previous ruling.

  ## Aircraft Integrity
    - Dismantling aircraft components to obtain materials for other purposes is strictly forbidden.
    - Ship doors must remain intact at all times.
    - Ship doors may not be tampered with in a way that causes them to remain INOP in flight (i.e. bolting them open then taking off.)

  ## Seating and Cargo
    - Seating capacity may be reduced to accommodate additional ammunition or cargo.
    - Seating may not be completely removed on the primary dropship; seating may be completely removed on the Gunship if it is NOT the only operable ship.

  ## Primary Transport Role
    - If a dropship becomes inaccessible or inoperable, another aircraft must assume the transport role.
    - The replacement aircraft must be configured with appropriate troop seating whenever possible.

  ## Parachute Operations
    - When conducting parachute drops, the Flight Crew are responsible for:
      - Ensuring the drop zone is safe.
      - Notifying personnel when to deploy.
      - Blind Drops are permitted with groups of four or fewer members and with permission from a member of the command staff.
      - Blind Drops with five or more members require a scout first, then all remaining personnel drop at their location via a flare or laser-designated mark, also requiring command staff permission.
</Document>
