<Document>
  # Minor Crimes
    These crimes are of low severity and can alternatively be punished with an NJP.

  ## Failure to Follow Procedure
    Failing to follow the regulations found in the Standard Operating Procedure.
      - 10 Minutes, equipment confiscation where relevant.

  ## Failure to Attend Combative Briefing
    Failing to attend briefing as a combative personnel (Ex., squad members, vehicle crew, intel personnel) without a valid reason (waiting in the requisitions line, gearing up after late wake-up, still equipping weapon systems to a vehicle, etc)
      - 5 Minutes

  ## Smoking in Medical Areas
    Smoking in areas designated for use by medical personnel, such as the entire medbay and surgical rooms.
      - NJP

  ## Hooliganism
    Behaviour that is generally disruptive to the ship or installation and its personnel, which is classified as low-level shenanigans not deserving of more severe punishment. Things such as excessive window knocking, force-feeding or failing to conduct oneself properly during the briefing, such as climbing the Briefing overview.
      - 6 minutes.

  ## Trespassing
    Unauthorised access to an area which a person does not normally have access to, or without command/superior approval.
      - 9 minutes.

  ## Intoxication
    To consume alcohol, marijuana, or other substances, such as drugs, resulting in being mentally or physically impaired.
      - 10 minutes, extended until the person is no longer impaired.

  ## Theft
    To take items (or property) from another person or entity without their express permission, or to retain possession of items that have been taken without permission. This includes the removal of vendors from department areas without permission.
      - 10 minutes, and the item(s) returned to the owner for minor items (Vendors, food, clothing).
      - 20 minutes, and the item(s) returned to the owner for major items (Vehicles, weaponry, communication devices, ammunition)

  ## Disrespecting a Superior
    Using offensive names or being directly disrespectful to anyone of a higher rank or position.
      - NJP

  ## Insubordination
    To ignore or not execute the lawful orders of higher-ranking personnel.
      - 12 minutes.

  ## False Testimony
    To intentionally and willingly lie to an MP/Law Enforcement Officer, or deputised officer, during a criminal investigation with the intent to disrupt said investigation.
      - 5 minutes, in relation to a minor crime.
      - 15 minutes, in relation to a major crime.
      - 20 minutes, in relation to a capital crime.
</Document>