<Document>

  # The Geneva Conventions of 12th August 2106


  #  - CHAPTER I: GENERAL PROVISIONS.


# Article 1   Respect and Application of the Convention.

  All Parties are to have and show respect for the convention at all times in any circumstance, while also implementing it in both peacetime and wartime.

  The United Nations Interstellar Space Corps and everybody that has signed the convention are bound to apply the convention at all-times.

# Article 2   Non-International Conflicts.

  In the case of an armed conflict should arise without being of an international character, each involved party is to be bound to the following provisions:

  Anybody that is not taking any part in the hostilities, including armed forces personnel that have laid down their weapons, detained, wounded people and others, should be treated humanely, no matter their situation, race, religion, sex and other...

  The following acts are prohibited at any time and any place during the armed conflict:
  Violence to life and person; Murder, Mutilation, Hostage taking, torture, experimentation and unlawfull executions.
  Degrading acts to one's personal dignity.
  Anybody clearly marked with Medical Symbols is forbidden from being attacked unless posing a threat to anybody.

# Article 3   International Conflicts.

  In the case of an armed conflict should arise of international character, each party involved is to be bound to the following provisions:

  Anybody that is not taking any part in the hostilities, including armed forces personnel that have laid down their weapons, detained, wounded people and others, should be treated humanely, no matter their situation, race, religion, sex and other...

# Article 4   Neutral Powers.

  Neutral Parties shall always apply the Convention in their own territory and other parties territory when able.

  Any party part of the United Nations may be requested at any moment for military or humanitarian aid should it be needed.

  If an armed conflict should arise and there are present Neutral Forces in the Area, they should attempt their best to provide safety to any non-involved personnel in the conflict, providing a basic life net to anybody seeking refuge.

  Should the neutral force evacuate from the Area of the Conflict, they should attempt their best efforts on evacuating non-involved personnel requesting aid.

# Article 5   Non-Renunciation of Rights.

  Nobody may at any given circumstance renounce in part or entirely to the rights secured to them by the Convention.


  # - CHAPTER II: MEDICAL UNITS AND THE WOUNDED.


# Article 6   Protection and Care of Personnel.

  Any civilian, military personnel, or other that present injuries, sickness or other are bound to the following article.

  If someone is wounded or sick, they shall be treated humanely and tended for by any medical personnel or involved party in the nearing area. They shall not be judged based on their nationality, sex, religion, or any similar criteria. Leaving them without aid willingly is prohibited. The only exception being if the wounded’s recovery would put any other person in risk due to it being in an active firefight zone or other.

  No wounded or sick individual/group may be exposed to any conditions that could worsen their state willingly. Any attempt upon their lives is strictly prohibited.

  Any involved party that is planning on abandoning wounded behind due to them relocating or retreating should leave with them a part of its medical personnel and material to assist in their care.

# Article 7   Protection and Care of Medical Installations/Ships.

  Any civilian and military medical installation or personnel are bound to the following article.

  Civilian Medical Personnel are considered Non-Combatants, and should be treated as such. They shouldn’t be engaged by any force only for being seen treating anybody, no matter if hostile to one of the parties. Medical installations, as long as civilians, are also considered non-combative locations, and shouldn’t be engaged.

  Civilian and Military Medical Personnel may only become void of this article if seen acting in any sort of combat that isn’t self-defense.

  As for Civilian Medical Installations, they may only be engaged if any non-combatants have been evacuated, and it’s been confirmed that the installation is being utilized for combat purposes.

  As for military Medics, as long as they do not engage in hostile actions or aren’t armed with anything above a sidearm, they may not be fired upon. Military Medical Installations are to be refrained from direct hostile action equally as Civilian Installations, with the exception that it is being used for Combat Purposes.

# Article 8   Protection and Care of the Wounded.

  Any civilian, military member or other that presents injuries or sickness is bound to the following article.

  If any of the previously mentioned is found to be injured or sick, they are to be provided quality medical care, and protected from all sorts of risk.

  Willingly ignoring or not providing quality services to the wounded is prohibited under any circumstance, with the only exclusion being the wounded having extremely contagious disease or such that may endanger a bigger population.

  Apart from that, any dead person must be given a proper burial if the situation allows for it. Mass Graves should be avoided at all costs.

# Article 9   Search/Recovery of Casualties.

  When Medical or Emergency Service Personnels are committing to the duty of searching for any wounded or dead, they are to be refrained from being attacked and protected while they are committing to their duties. Both conflicting parties should always attempt a cease-fire during a period of time to allow for Emergency Services to recover the dead and wounded.

# Article 10    Evacuations.

  In the case of a Planet-Wide catastrophe during peacetime or wartime, a cease-fire should be put in place immediately to allow for all parties, involved or not, to evacuate the planet as soon as possible.

  Any force with space-travel capabilities is bound by convention to aid in the evacuation of all people on the Planet, and are to care for them until transported to a safe position. All Expenses are to be paid by the Sector Authority or the instigator of the catastrophe, if any.

  Willingly refusing to commit to the rescue of personnel stranded on the planet during an emergency is prohibited, and counts as a Crime against Humanity.

# Article 11    Role of the Emergency Services.

  The military authorities may appeal to the charity of the Planet’s Emergency Service Workers to voluntarily collect and care for, under their direction, the wounded and sick, granting persons who have responded to this appeal the necessary protection and facilities.

  Should the adverse Party take or retake control of the area, it shall likewise grant these persons the same protection and the same facilities. The military authorities shall permit the inhabitants and relief societies, even in invaded or occupied areas, spontaneously to voluntarily collect and care for wounded or sick of whatever nationality. The civilian population shall respect these wounded and sick, and are to abstain from offering them violence.

  No one may ever be molested or convicted for having aided the wounded or sick. The provisions of the present Article do not relieve the occupying Power of its obligation to give both physical and moral care to the wounded and sick.


  # - CHAPTER III: MILITARY PERSONNEL, INSTALLATIONS.


# Article 12    Protected Personnel.

  Military Personnel such as Medical staff, Chaplains, and any other non-combative role, as long as they aren't acting in a hostile manner, are bound to the following article.

  The aforementioned personnel are to be protected from any hostilities as long as they aren’t acting against their role's ‘Non-Combative’ description. Carrying a side-arm isn't a reason for considering them hostile.

  Any Military Personnel that’s in Hypersleep is also considered under protection, and may not be fired upon while they sleep or right after they wake up.

# Article 13    Military Installations.

  Military Installations are all cleared to engage to the discretion of the Parties Armed Forces Command, with exception of Medical Installations and Hypersleep Chambers, which may not be shot unless being used for Combat-Use.

# Article 14    Surrendering Personnel/Installations.

  Any Military Personnel that has laid down their weapons and has surrendered is bound to the following article.

  If an individual or group of individuals of a party surrender to the adverse party, they may not be engaged, and must be taken for arrest or re-directed to another unit at the adverse party commander's will.

  Any arrested individual is to receive fair treatment, aid and protection, and are bound to the rights given by Article 28.


  # - CHAPTER IV: DISTINCTIVE EMBLEM.


#  Article 15    The Emblem of the Convention.

  The Emblem of the Convention is always portrayed as a Red Cross, which can be worn as an armband, appear on a vest, a vehicle, helicopter, etcetera... Utilizing the emblem for reasons hostile to the Convention is prohibited.

# Article 16    Identification of Civilian Personnel.

  Civilian personnel is any individual that is wearing or carrying everything except the following:

  Any sort of military-grade weaponry and actively using it for hostile reasons.
  Any sort of military-grade uniform or equipment.

  As a civilian, wearing this makes you be identified as an enemy by any party, and being engaged for it will not carry consequences to the party that engaged.

# Article 17    Identification of Medical Personnel.

  Medical Personnel is any individual that is wearing any sort of red or green cross and are unarmed and showing no sights of clear hostility [Hostility that may endanger lives].

  They may not be engaged under any circumstance, unless they are abusing the cross for hostile acts or for their own benefit, and aren’t really a medic.

# Article 18    Identification of Military Personnel.

  Military Personnel is any individual wearing a combination of distinct patches, uniform, equipment and weaponry from a specific party.

  The only circumstances that they may not be engaged is when they’re injured, have surrendered or no longer pose any threat.

# Article 19    Wrong Usage of Emblems.

  Wrongful use of emblems for personal gain, false flag attacks, infiltrating, or any other act that goes against the emblem is for, is prohibited, and a grave breach of the convention.


  # - CHAPTER V: THE RULES OF WAR.


# Article 20    Weapons of Mass Destruction.

  This article is bound for any type of weapon which may cause catastrophic planetary-sized, orbital-sized, and other, results.

  Weaponry such as Armed Satellites made to prevent anybody leaving the planet, wide-spread use of nuclear weaponry, planet killers, chemical weapons, biological weapons and any other weapon that may cause mass destruction.

  Only exceptions are in case of responding to System, Sector and Galaxy threatening situations. For example, Armed Satellites may be used to prevent anybody leaving a planet due to an infection that may spread through the entire system rapidly.

# Article 21    Chemical Weaponry.

  Chemical weaponry designed to kill or cause unnecessary pain upon an individual or group of individuals are bound to the following article.

  Chemical weaponry such as gases, corrosive compounds, nerve agents, blister agents, and others are prohibited for use under all circumstances against human targets, this is considered a Crime Against Humanity. Use exceptions made for Hostile Xenofauna as long as it may not cause side-effects to surrounding areas or populations.

# Article 22    Biological Weaponry.

  Biological Weapons designed to kill or cause unnecessary pain upon an individual or group of individuals are bound to the following article.

  Biological Weapons such as parasitic lifeforms, infective organisms, engineered viruses and any other biological agent designed for killing, wounding or contaminating anything or anyone is prohibited, and considered a Crime against Humanity.

# Article 23    Alien Weaponry.

  Any advanced weaponry that isn’t of human origin is bound to the following article.

  Utilizing any sort of advanced alien technology is prohibited under any circumstances, utilizing it against any human party, if destructive enough, may be considered a Crime Against Humanity.

# Article 24    Autonomous Combat Weaponry.

  Any combat system that may work without the active supervision of a human operator is bound to the following article.

  The use of any sort of Autonomous Combat Weaponry, such as Synthethics, is strictly prohibited and considered a Crime Against Humanity.

# Article 25    Orbital Weaponry.

  Any Space to Ground ship-launched or orbitally-launched equipment is bound to the following article.

  Weaponry that may be launched from orbit towards the planet below is to be used sparingly due to the destruction it may bring, and the unreliability of targeting systems. Weapons such as Orbital Bombardments are to be used only when the Zone of Effect is cleared of any Non-Combative Personnel.

  Orbitally-Launched Tactical Nuclear Weaponry is prohibited during peacetime when dealing with insurgencies, this also applies to Orbital Bombardments, which may not be used against insurgencies.

  Specially protected environments such as forests or other may not see Large-Scale Orbital Weaponry used upon them.

  Breaches of this Article by a high-extent will be prosecuted as a Crime Against Humanity depending on the casualties provoked by this.

  Incendiary and Cluster Orbital Bombardments, apart from the previously stated criteria, may only be used in Desert or Snowy Planets, away from Colonies.

# Article 26    Area Denial Weaponry.

  Any sort of Area Denial Weapon, such as Cluster or Incendiary Munitions, are bound to the following article.

  Airplane/Dropship and other Cluster and incendiary Munitions are illegal to utilize in cities if there is confirmed civilian presence. If the entire city is confirmed to be cleared, said weapons are authorized only against enemy targets. Hospitals should be spared whenever able.

  Orbital Bombardment ADW, if approving the previous criteria, may be utilized at the discretion of the parties Command forces, any failure in the guiding system or other that causes the Orbital to go off-track and hit anything that isn’t the objective may carry repercussions.

  Utilizing flamethrower equipment on any sort of vehicle or gun towards civilian personnel is strictly prohibited.

# Article 27    Electronic Weapons and Cyber Attacks.

  Electronic Weaponry such as EMPs, and others, along with Cyberattacks fall under the following article.

  The use of indiscriminate EMPs to directly hinder or use that may hinder as a secondary effect vital civilian infrastructure such as hospitals, police stations, or other, is strictly prohibited.

  Cyber attacks that attack infrastructure such as banks, hospitals, or other are also strictly prohibited.

  The only circumstance where EWs and CAs are legal is when one party is attempting to hinder systems of the opposing party.

  Use of these weapons during peacetime, unless against insurgencies, is strictly forbidden.


  # - CHAPTER VI: GENERAL PROTECTIONS OF PRISONERS OF WAR


# Article 28    Treatment of Prisoners.

  Any member of a government army that has been arrested is considered a prisoner of war from the moment they get captured; Anybody meeting that criteria is bound to the following article.

  All prisoners of war are to receive adequate and quality medical aid, food, shelter and protection. They should be treated humanely regardless of their nationality, race, sex, faction, or other.

  The detaining party is responsible for caring for the prisoners of war until they can be transferred.

  Deliberatedly ignoring the Prisoner's needs or this article on itself is prohibited, and may be considered a Crime against Humanity.

# Article 29    Prohibited use of Torture.

  The use of any sort of torture, cruel treatment, coercive interrogations and any other cruel punishments are prohibited.

  No human may be subject to any of the aforementioned situations, breaking this article is considered Crimes Against Humanity.

  Exceptions of this are when information that may save multiple lives is at stake, although excess violence may not be used.

# Article 30    Hostage Taking.

  The act of kidnapping anybody for personal, criminal, military or political gain is prohibited, and may not be used to gain leverage towards a party. This includes utilizing civilians as shields.

  During Wartime, capturing anyone during an operation made specifically for capturing isn’t considered a hostage taking, and should not be punished for it.


  # - CHAPTER VII: GENERAL PROTECTIONS OF CIVILIANS.


# Article 31    Vital Colony Infrastructure.

  Any sort of Atmospheric Reactors, Water Purification Facilities, and other essential life-support infrastructure are considered vital infrastructure and protected assets. Attacking these is considered a Crime against Humanity, as it causes unnecessary pain, and for the Reactors, may cause an ecological-collapse.

  This infrastructure may only be attacked when all civilian population has been evacuated for the planet, and if it’s currently being used by a hostile party as a combat position.

# Article 32    Genocides.

  The deliberate extermination of a human population, protected group, or other, is prohibited under any circumstance, and considered a Crime Against Humanity.

  This englobes acts that intend to destroy in whole, or in part, a prospective population. Direct Violent Actions, deliberatedly deprivating, and other actions designated to eliminate a population are extremely illegal and a breach of the convention.

# Article 33    Distress Signal Integrity.

  Distress Signals may only be utilized for emergencies, false calls or utilizing the Distress Signal to lure a party into somewhere is prohibited.

# Article 34    Forced Relocation.

  The forced relocation of a whole or part of a human population or protected species is prohibited. Evacuating colonies due to an active planet, solar or sector threat is not considered ‘Forced Relocation’ as a crime.

# Article 35    Slavery and Forced Labor.

  Utilizing Human or Protected Species manpower illegally for forced labor and slavery is prohibited, and considered a Crime Against Humanity. Any worker should be paid correctly and left enough time for rest and recreational activities.

# Article 36    Wellbeing of Civilian Personnel.

  Civilians shall be protected, given aid, and other, at any given time, and shouldn’t be abused, molested, threatened, relocated, humiliated and other.

# Article 37    Collective Punishment.

  Any punishment shall only be given to the responsible individual or group of individuals that are wanted, and punishment shall not be imposed upon innocent groups or individuals that haven’t done anything.

  Any sort of reprisal or retaliatory action against a group of individuals is considered a breach of this article, and depending on how grave the reprisal was, it may or may not be considered a Crime against Humanity.

  This goes for Colonists, Corporations, Protected Species and others. This does not include Military NJPs.

# Article 39    Civilian Rights.

  They have rights to free speech, proper protection from threats, access to food and water, access to proper hygienic and medical installations, recreational activities, and other. They shall not be abused in any way by any party.

  All colonists are bound to Civilian Law at all times, and must follow army orders during martial law.


  # - CHAPTER VIII: GENERAL PROTECTIONS OF SPACE-BORNE VESSELS


# Article 39    Identified Civilian Vessels.

  Any sort of civilian vessel that is legally identified is bound to the following article.

  They may not be attacked in ship to ship combat under any circumstance unless confirmed to pose a threat to something or someone in the sector. As for boardings, it is legal and requires a warrant, with the one exception being if there is a present threat.

# Article 40    Unidentified Vessels.

  Any vessel not identified by Military or Police Signals is bound to the following article.

  If a Vessel doesn’t identify itself after three hails, boarding action is approved and legal without a warrant. Any ship-to-ship engagement is forbidden unless they are a threat.

  Abandoned Vessels may firstly be investigated by Police or Military Salvage teams before they can be scrapped to check for any survivors and rule out the cause for the scuttle.

# Article 41    Military Vessels.

  Military Vessels have got permission to patrol any area within their limits at any given time. They must always keep their IFF on for identification and may not deploy upon a colony not under their jurisdiction without prior approval from the colonial administration or the party overseeing the colony.

# Article 42    Surrendering Vessels.

  Any sort of Vessel, no matter their type, nationality, or other, if surrendering, may be taken in by the adverse party to which it is surrendering. The surrendering vessel may only be scuttled after all personnel are evacuated from it.

  No surrendering vessel may be shot unless it still poses an active threat, or is false-flagging its surrender.

# Article 43    Evacuation Pods.

  Evacuation Pods may be recovered only by Police and Military Parties when able, if none nearby, civilians may also take them in, but they may not open the pod.

  Pods are forbidden from being shot at unless they’re being utilized as a weapon or carrying a threat.

</Document>
